Here's how I'm defining the context targets around a given word index.
下面说说我是如何定义给定索引的上下文字词的
First, according to the excerpt from the paper,
首先 根据之前从论文中摘录的一段文字
I'm going to define a range R. R is going to be
我将定义范围 R
a random integer in the range one to c, the window size.
R 是从 1 到 C 的一个随机整数，C 是窗口大小
randint takes in a range that is not inclusive of the last number.
randint() 获取一个不包含最后一个数字的范围
So, that's why I have a plus one here.
因此这里是 +1
Then I define the start and stop indices of my context window.
然后定义上下文窗口的 start 和 stop 索引
The start will be a range of words in the past.
start 是过去字词的范围
That is the index of my word of interest minus my range R.
等于目标字词的索引减去范围 R
This will only happen as long as that doesn't get us to a negative index.
前提是索引不是负数
If this operation does give us a negative value,
如果这个运算的结果是负数
then I just set my start index to the startup my list of words index zero.
那么将 start 索引设为字词列表的起始索引 0
Then my stop index is where my feature words end.
stop 索引是特征字词的结束位置
So, my word of interests index,
即目标字词的索引
plus our range R. Finally,
加上范围 R
I do not want my return target context to include the word at the past in index.
最后 我不希望返回的上下文包含传入索引对应的字词
So, I'm defining my target words as the words
因此将 target_words 定义为
behind my index of interest from start to idx,
从 start 到 idx 的字词
plus the words in front,
以及
idx plus one to stop plus one.
从 idx+1 到 stop+1 的字词
Then I'm returning these words as a list.
然后以列表形式返回这些字词
Then when I go to test this out on a test set of word tokens,
使用字词标记测试集测试这段代码
and I can run this a couple of times,
并运行几次代码
I see that I get a variable length of words around my past an index of five.
获得了传入索引 5 周围的几个字词
I can see the target does not include my index of interest.
可以看出 Target 不包含目标索引
These line up just because I've created some input data,
这一行数字是我创建的输入数据
that's the integer zero through nine.
它们是从 0 到 9 的整数
If you run the cell multiple times,
如果运行此单元格多次
you will see a different target based on a different
将会看到不同的上下文字词
randomly generated R. So, this looks good.
因为随机生成了不同的 R
Right below this function,
我在此函数下面
I've defined a generator function.
定义了生成器函数
This function we'll use our get_target function that we've just defined.
此函数将利用我们刚刚定义的 get_target() 函数
get_batches takes in a list of word tokens a batch_size and a window_size.
get_batches() 的输入参数是字词标记列表 批次大小和窗口大小
It makes sure that we can make complete batches of data.
它确保我们能创建完整的数据批次
In this four loop, I'm iterating over our words one batch length at a time.
在这个 for 循环里 我会一次遍历一批数据
I get a batch of words then for each word in a batch I'm calling get_target.
获取一批数据 然后对这批数据里的每个字词都调用 get_target
This should return a batch of target words in a window around the given batch word.
返回给定批次字词周围的窗口里的上下文字词
I'm calling extend here so that each batch x and y will be one row of values.
在这里调用 extend() 使每批 x 和 y 都是一行值
Here, I'm making x the same length as y.
使 x 的长度与 y 一样
Finally, it returns this list of input words x and target context words why using yield,
最后 使用 yield 返回输入字词 x 和上下文字词 y 列表
which makes this a generator function.
所以这是一个生成器函数
Then in the blue cell,
在下面的单元格中
we can test this batching out to see what it
我们将代码应用到虚拟数据上
looks like when applied to some fake data here.
看看这个批次生成函数的效果如何
So, I'm getting an x and y batch of data by calling next on our generator function.
对生成器函数调用 next() 并获得 x 和 y 批次数据
Here, I've passed in some int_text,
在这里传入整数文本
a batch_size of four, and a window_size of five.
将批次大小设为 4 并将窗口大小设为 5
When I run this cell,
运行此单元格
this output might look a little weird because everything's been extended into one row.
输出看起来有点怪 因为数据都扩展成了一行
But I can see that I've made my desired four batches
但是可以看出我获得了期望的 4 个批次
because I have four different input x values;
因为这里有四组不同的输入值 x
zero, one, two, and three.
分别是 0、1、2、3
If we take a look at the first input zero,
看看第一组输入 0
we see is length three.
发现长度是 3
So, the target must have also been length three.
因此目标 y 的长度肯定也是 3
The corresponding context is one, two, three.
相应的上下文是 1、2、3
All the targets in the future window that surround
表示输入索引 0 周围的未来窗口中的所有上下文字词
the input index zero, which is what I expect.
和我们预期的一样
For the other input, output batches,
对于其他输入输出批次
I can see that I'm generating targets that surround the input values one, two, and three.
可以看出我生成了输入值 1、2 和 3 周围的上下文字词
So, we have our batch inputs,
我们已经获得了批次输入数据
and our target context.
以及上下文字词
Now, we can get to defining and training a word to vec model on this batch data,
接下来我们将定义 Word2Vec 模型
which I'll go over next.
并用这些批次数据训练该模型